HI removed, cleaned
and corrected by Lunar Team
He's from the AG's office.
We're catching a hot one.
Hooray. I was about to go mad
with boredom.
Don't say, "Hooray". Someone's died.
Well, if they have, my happiness
makes no difference to them.
Nor does catching their killer,
for that matter.
True, but it makes a difference
to the killer.
This e-mail came
to the attorney general's office...
...and the governor's office
20 minutes ago.
"Pay attention.
At exactly 11:05 a.m. today...
...at 35.04 north and 116.49 west...
...you'll see an arrogant and greedy person
punished with death...
...and you will know I am serious."
Signed, "Joe Q Public."
- Interesting.
- It's probably nothing.
- Why can't local police handle it?
- Some fool let the governor read the thing.
He talks to the AG,
the AG talks to Minelli...
...and Minelli tells me
we have to handle it personally.
Rigsby, you're the fastest driver.
If we leave now
we can get there by 11:05.
- Where is it?
- Mojave Desert. Middle of nowhere.
- Quarter of a mile off the highway.
- Interesting.
- Boring. Three hours away.
- Desert's beautiful this time of year.
Let's all go.
We can bring a picnic lunch.
Someone has to stay
and answer the phones.
- How much further?
- About 50 feet.
Look at that. Look what I found.
What is it?
It's a worm. It's a fossilized worm.
I'm happy for you.
All right, this is it. This is the spot.
11:04 and change. Right on time.
- For what?
- There's still fifteen seconds to go.
You know, when this worm was alive,
this desert was the floor of a great sea.
There were dinosaurs swimming
above us.
- That is kind of awesome.
- Yeah.
Sharks the size of buses.
Brilliantly colored sea monsters.
Those mountains,
they would have been volcanoes.
This is a goat turd,
about six months old.
Still, giant sharks, here.
Okay, we've done our job. Somebody
yanked our chain pretty good. Let's go.
- Wait. I think we should wait.
- What for? What could possibly happen?
I have no idea. But it's a pleasant spot,
and I have sandwiches.
Eat them in the car.
We've wasted enough time.
- Hey, do you hear that?
- Yeah.
What is that?
Our victim's name is David Whittaker.
One of a party of six skydivers that
went up with an instructor this morning.
All executives of a company
called Carnelian Prime Trust...
...out on an outdoor adventure retreat.
Our victim was VP of Human Resources.
David Whittaker, Carnelian Prime Trust.
Got it. I'll start digging.
See that? Right here?
That's the master strap, okay?
And it was cut nearly clean through.
That has to be deliberate,
and that is evil.
The minute this thing deployed,
the chute would have come clean off.
- Who rigged the chute?
- Me. I did. Last night.
And I double-checked every one of them.
They were A-okay. I guarantee it.
- This was done after.
- By someone that knows parachutes.
Yes.
I've been rigging chutes for 15 years.
I've never had one accident. Not one.
There's a number on there.
Is there any way to identify
which chute is for which jumper?
Are they assigned to individuals?
I tell the jumpers
to grab the first chute they come to.
Those numbers are strictly
for the maintenance logs.
Who had access to the chutes
after you rigged them?
They're in the hangar overnight.
It's not locked.
So anyone who had access
to the airport, basically.
Agent Lisbon, is it?
We're leaving. Keep my office informed.
And you'll be hearing from our lawyers.
- Do it now.
- Gonna let him get away with that?
- Mr. Faulk.
- Hold on.
This is a murder investigation.
You can't leave
until we say you can leave.
I apologize. I thought we had answered
all your questions.
Do we have your permission to leave,
Agent Lisbon?
Yes. But we're gonna have
follow-up questions.
You know our location.
Yes, we do.
We'll be in touch, Mr. Faulk.
- Why isn't the body on the move yet?
- Forensics is still working the scene.
He fell from the sky.
What could they work on for an hour?
Nerds, they won't be hurried.
So who is this Randall Faulk guy?
President and CEO
of Carnelian Prime Trust.
One of the top 10
private equity firms in the world.
They buy and sell big companies.
Oil, steel, auto plants, hotel chains.
You name it, they own it.
Rich bastards.
As soon as the scene's clear,
go to the airport.
Find out who had access
to the parachutes last night.
And find out about Spruell's history.
See if anything bumps.
You got it, boss.
Van Pelt, what's up?
- You close to a TV?
- No. Why?
Aw, hell.
Want your sandwich?
Help you?
- We're looking for Mr. Faulk.
- Right up at the house.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Following Mr. Whittaker's horrific death...
...a message was sent
within the past hour to the police...
...and several media outlets,
including Channel 4 News.
It reads, "I have proved my strength.
I have scored one for the little guy,
and I will do it again...
...unless Carnelian Prime Trust
makes a public apology...
...for its greed and arrogance,
and promises to change its ways.
Yours truly, Joe Q Public."
- Illiterate nonsense.
- Perhaps.
But the threat to your lives is explicit.
We need to set up a security plan
with the marshal.
What time are you planning
on going back to the city?
We're not.
We're staying here.
We're continuing the retreat.
For God's sake, Rand.
Perhaps there are other
considerations here?
I'm not sure staying here
is the most advisable posture.
We stay. I'm not letting
some random lunatic disturb Carnelian.
This is a test of our strength.
David would want us to continue.
Yes, he would. Yes, he would.
David would never back down.
David wouldn't want you to respectfully
acknowledge his tragic and untimely death?
Oh, well, okay.
He wouldn't want it to interfere
with your kayaking schedule.
- Joan, is it?
- Jane. Like the girl.
- Jane.
- Mr. Jane.
- Thank you.
This week that we spend here
is not a vacation. This is a test.
What we learn here about ourselves
and about each other...
...is at the core of the philosophy
of Carnelian's success.
There will come an appropriate moment
to mourn our dear friend.
This is the moment
to show resolve and courage.
And now perhaps you can give us
a briefing on the case so far.
We investigate murders.
We don't give briefings.
Why on earth not?
We have the right to know.
- We're the victims here.
- David Whittaker is the victim.
Any of us could have picked that chute.
Any of us could be dead right now.
Yes. The saboteur didn't know
which of you would die.
He felt that any one of you
would fit the bill.
Greedy and arrogant.
- How does that make you feel?
- Oh, is this group therapy?
You want group therapy?
No, we want a professional
police detective.
I will be speaking with your superiors
to assure myself...
- ...that your people are the best option.
- A good assurance to get.
What is the worst thing
you people have done lately?
We control assets of over $50 billion.
Our companies employ
over half a million people.
The way the economy's been going...
...I've been forced to put 50,000
men and women out of work.
Some of them will blame Carnelian
for their misfortunes, I'm sure.
- It's understandable.
- Does that bother you, personally?
It most certainly does. I am concerned
about security just like anyone else.
- I don't consider myself bulletproof.
- That's not what I meant.
Does it bother you that people
are out of work on your say-so?
No. That's my job.
To make the tough decisions.
Tough, yet rational and ethical.
And, yes, I'm afraid
people will suffer because of it.
So it's no surprise that someone's
making a stand against you?
No. There's always malcontents
amongst us. I'll send you our register.
- You have a register of malcontents?
- Anyone who's sued us or threatened to.
Written hostile letters, that sort of thing.
They're in the register.
- It'd be good for us to take a look.
- Yeah.
We'd like a list of everyone
with a security pass.
- You have a warrant?
- It's not privileged information.
- You can give it to us without prejudice.
- Well, okay, if you're sure.
Yeah, I'm sure. if you could send it
to that address, please.
Hey, you'll be getting the airport list
any second now.
Okay.
Got it. I'll crosscheck it
against the Carnelian list.
One name on both lists. Lee Skelling.
Lee Skelling?
Yeah, he works the baggage truck
a couple days a week.
- He's not here today.
- Okay, thank you.
- Thanks, Van Pelt.
- Yep.
Sniveling lackey pigs is what you are,
you know that? Damn lackeys.
- Calm down, Lee.
- Make me.
Stop right there.
You let him go right now, you hear me?
It's not loaded.
Now, you put that down right now,
you idiot.
- But, Daddy...
- Get inside, boy.
- Scared the pants off you, didn't he?
- Yeah, he did.
No, he didn't.
Two years ago, you sent this letter
to Carnelian headquarters.
"You greedy sons of bitches
ought to know better than to steal...
...from decent citizens like myself.
You're no better than scum in my book.
You better pay up
or there's gonna be consequences."
- Recall writing this letter?
- Yes, I do.
Tell me about it.
Like the letter says,
which I wrote in a moment of anger...
...they stole from me.
From my family. When I called them on it,
they not only didn't pay me...
...they did their damnedest
to throw me in jail.
- How did they steal from you?
- I used to work at Grant Aerospace.
Fan ducts for airliners.
They had a whole incentive thing going.
If a floor guy comes up with an idea
that saves costs or speeds the line...
...he gets a bonus.
Fifty thousand dollars.
I came up with an improvement
on the riveting gear...
...that saved them five and a half cents
per unit. That's huge.
- So 50,000 for me, right?
- That's a lot of money.
The CEO shook my hand.
I had it in writing.
Then Carnelian Prime buys
Grant Aerospace.
Come time to pay my bonus,
they welsh.
I complained about it, they sacked me.
- What did you do then?
- Oh, I tried to take them to court.
Me and one old cross-eyed lawyer
out of the phone book...
...against 20 Ivy League weasels.
No contest.
- I didn't even get a hearing.
- Sounds like a bad injustice was done.
- Sounds like you have a right to be angry.
- Yes, I do. I do have a right.
Your friends already took Lee.
What do you want?
Jessie Skelling?
No, I'm Cindy Crawford.
Jessie's on vacation in Mexico.
Ma'am?
I can't even look at you people,
you make me so mad.
Lee's done nothing. Nothing.
Jessie, if your husband is innocent,
we're your best friends.
We'll prove he's innocent.
Will you help us?
You want some water or a soda?
Some water sounds lovely.
Where were you the night before last,
from 9 p.m. till 9 the next morning?
I was at work and then I was at home.
- At work at the airport?
- Yes.
And, yes, I could have
gotten into Spruell's hangar...
...and messed with that parachute,
but I didn't.
I worked my shift, I went home,
and that's all I did.
I didn't know those Carnelian people
were out there jumping that day.
You know what?
I wouldn't give a damn if I did know.
No?
Okay, yeah, I would give a damn.
They could have given me that money.
It was peanuts to them. Nothing.
But cut a man's chute? No.
Four years with the Rangers.
- You're familiar with parachutes.
- Yes, I am.
- You even been in the military, Cho?
- Yes.
Then you know.
I would chop a man's head off
and pee down his neck...
...before I'd ever cut his chute that way.
I mean, that's bad.
That's out there.
Lee is a God-fearing man.
He wouldn't kill somebody like that.
- No way.
- He was a soldier. He can kill.
- For his country. Not for himself.
- What's the difference, you think?
I don't know.
But it makes all the difference.
You're very confident of his innocence.
How can you be so sure?
Because I asked him if he did it,
and he said, no, he didn't do it.
Ah. You suspected
he might indeed have done it.
- But he denied it. You believe him.
- Lee don't lie to me.
He'll cause me trouble and grief
a hundred ways, but he don't lie to me.
Wives often say that
about their husbands.
Easy to fool yourself
that the people you love are honest.
Yeah, it is.
But I know he wouldn't lie.
- Why?
- Because.
- Because I'm dying.
He wouldn't lie to somebody who's gonna
sit next to the Almighty pretty soon.
I'm sorry.
Stuff happens. Don't worry about it.
What time did Lee get home?
Same time as every night,
about half past midnight.
Yeah.
My husband did not do this thing.
If he went into jail,
what would happen to the kids?
They'd go into care.
And he wouldn't do that to me.
He wouldn't.
Thank you for your time.
Your wife said
you wouldn't do that to her.
I don't know. Maybe if you thought
you could get away with it, you would.
When I was working at Grant Aerospace,
Jessie was getting the best treatment.
If I hadn't made a nuisance of myself,
I'd still have my job...
...and my health insurance.
Jessie would be okay.
So why did I bitch and moan, right?
I mean, why couldn't I just be quiet?
Keep my job?
I don't know.
Ego and pride and vanity, I expect.
Yeah, I guess something like that.
But if I thought
I could get away with it?
Yes, I would kill
every last one of those bastards.
But you can't kill rich people
and get away with it.
Everybody knows that.
- I know. I can read your mind.
- Oh, you can?
You're thinking Mr. Skelling
is innocent and we should release him. Cho.
That's amazing.
That's exactly what I was thinking.
Let me try. You're thinking:
"Jane is right, the man is innocent.
We should let him go."
No. I think you want him to be innocent
because his guilt would be too simple.
- He has motive, opportunity and no alibi.
- Yeah...
- Yeah, boss?
- Let Lee Skelling go.
You sure?
- We have no hard evidence against him.
- Okay, will do.
We should talk
to the Carnelian executives.
- Throw a cat among the pigeons.
- You think? Why?
What if this is not what it looks like?
- What if it's about something else?
- Like?
- I don't know.
- So you're suggesting we throw...
- ...a blind cat among the pigeons?
- Yeah.
No.
Howdy.
I understand that you released
a promising suspect.
Eh. We didn't like him for it.
We think... Well, that is, I think.
Agent Lisbon disagrees with me.
I think the answer lies
with one of you here.
- Well, that's absurd.
- Why?
You think one of us
sabotaged David's parachute?
Why not?
The chutes were clearly numbered.
The saboteur would simply have
to make sure not to choose the dud.
But how could they know
who would pick the dud?
They'd be killing
a randomly selected colleague.
- Why would anyone wanna do that?
- Yes. I don't know.
We'll find out.
So tell us a little about yourselves.
Let's use this sadness
to get some real truths, shall we?
- Joyce, you first.
- Me first to do what exactly?
I'll tell you what I think,
to get the ball rolling.
I think you've made your way
in the world...
...by concealing your true feelings
under a mask of positivity and niceness.
But underneath, you're a seething mass
of ugly, bitter resentment.
You think Faulk is a stupid buffoon,
but you're far too clever...
- ...to be brave enough to tell him so.
- How dare you?
And you, Mr. Braemar.
- Marine Corps, yes?
- Yes.
Office politics must seem
kind of trivial in comparison.
You fantasize about
pulling a couple of weapons...
...and showing these civilians
a little reality?
That is baseless, inappropriate,
and I resent it.
Agent Lisbon,
this is a high-profile case.
A career-making case
if concluded successfully.
Is this how you wish to proceed?
With clownish games?
I apologize. Mr. Jane is a consultant.
His statements in no way reflect
the official view of the CBI.
I am simply trying to get a full picture
of the group dynamic here.
Anyone resent the sexual relationship
between Faulk and Miss Sobell here?
Anyone?
Why would anyone resent it?
Don't engage with him, Nadia.
- Oh, you let him tell you what to do?
- That's enough.
- You can go now.
- Yes, we can.
You threw a cat, all right.
What valuable insight did you glean
as a result?
Nothing. It's a little disappointing.
Well, maybe, just maybe, this case
is exactly what it looks like it's about.
Bitter unsubs with a grudge
against the fat cats.
Nice drive, though.
Nice three-hour drive.
I'm hungry. You hungry?
- Ready?
- Ready.
Know what's weird about those guys?
None of them seem to give a damn.
A colleague of theirs falls out of the sky
and they seem okay with it.
Is that guilt or indifference?
Corporate brainwashing.
Turns them into robots.
- Grief isn't productive, and that's all.
- I don't buy that.
People make up their own minds.
You can't brainwash them.
Sure, you can. That's what these
corporate retreats are about.
It's primitive brainwashing
via group suffering.
It's like office karaoke
or fraternity hazing.
How so?
When the individual is humiliated,
their perceived value of the group is raised.
I went on a retreat when I got promoted
to head of the unit. I wasn't humiliated.
- I wasn't brainwashed.
- So you say.
- I wasn't. it was useful, actually.
- How so?
Learning about communication
and leadership skills. Building trust.
Something you could profit from.
What does that mean?
Like you don't know
you have major trust issues?
I trust people. I trust you.
No, you don't. I don't trust you either.
It's upsetting to hear that.
- You don't trust me?
- Of course not.
How many times have you lied to me?
Misled me? Tricked me?
- Is that trust? No.
- Well, we have to remedy this.
- Let's do a trust fall.
- A trust fall?
Yeah, I'm sure you did one
on your CBI retreat.
It's when you fall backward
and I catch you.
Oh, yes. We did do that.
- No.
- You won't?
- We have a long drive still.
- Here we have two coworkers...
...recognizing the boundaries
of their professional relationship.
You wanna trust me,
but there's something holding you back.
Yes. You're untrustworthy.
It's my job not to trust you.
Lisbon, I want you to know
that you can trust me.
No matter what happens,
I will be there for you. I will.
I need you to know that.
- Now, can I catch you?
- Come on.
Please?
Fine.
Come on.
See? You can trust me.
Oh, wow, that worked.
Suddenly I trust you.
Aha.
I allow you to drive me
around the country in this contraption.
That's serious trust.
That was
a classic rendition of "Paris Nights."
- Now it's back to jazz on KRA...
- Talk to me.
Do I have to?
No, I can just fall asleep and we can drift
into oncoming traffic. Your call.
- Have you seen any good movies lately?
- No. You?
No.
Interesting.
Lisbon, we just got another message
from Joe Q Public.
"When all go to bed
they best say their goodbyes."
"For prompt at my bidding,
all things will rise."
"And the king of the rats
will meet his demise."
Signed, "Joe Q Public."
- Is that all?
- Yeah, that's all.
- Okay.
- Okay, bye.
Now he's writing bad poetry.
What does that mean,
"All things will rise"?
Oh.
What? What does it mean?
He's planted a bomb to kill Faulk.
What the hell?
- What are you doing?
- Bear with us.
- We have reason to believe...
- There it is.
- Told you so.
- There's what?
There's no need to gloat.
There is an explosive device...
- ...under your bed.
- Oh, my God.
- Wait.
- Wait?
Just let me get a better look.
No, I don't think there's
a pressure trigger. You can get up now.
- You don't think?
- It doesn't.
Timer's set to go off in 10 minutes,
we have plenty of time.
If you'll just get out of the bed slowly.
We do not wanna jar the device
in any way.
Boom.
For God's sakes.
Sorry, I couldn't resist.
- It didn't go off. What happened?
- She's a nasty little girl.
Anyone inside of 20 feet
would have been a red mist.
See this wire right here?
Yeah, it came loose at some point,
disarmed her.
- Silly mistake.
- Lucky, huh?
Don't touch that.
Even though it's disarmed...
...if you touch the red terminal
we're all barbecue.
Oh, well, that's good to know.
- Looks like expert work.
- Absolutely.
You've got high-test Army ordnance
combined with a hobby-store trigger.
Whoever built this
really knows his onions.
- Army ordnance?
- Yeah.
You've got the innards of five Mark I-9
Army-issue grenades packed together.
Soon as he heard about the bomb,
he knew you people would be on him.
So he grabbed his gear
and he lit out of here.
- How did he know about the bomb?
- I told him.
I listen to the police scanner.
Kind of a hobby.
You hear some things, my God.
- Where did he go? His truck's still here.
- Friend gave him a ride.
- Friend's name?
- Sure, like I'm gonna tell you.
Lee's only making things worse
by running.
Right.
He said to tell you that he is
100 percent innocent. He didn't do it.
But that's no matter,
once the law gets you.
- You know where's he gone?
- Wouldn't you like to know.
- I know. Just wondering if you do.
- Yeah? Where'd he go?
The mountains.
You're welcome to look.
You won't find him.
I bet you're right.
Capable man, your husband.
- Yes, he is.
- Is he armed?
If he is, it's for hunting and nothing else.
Send him my best wishes
next time you speak to him.
I will.
- Damn it, I should have never let him go.
- He didn't do it.
Maybe he didn't,
but it sure looks like he did.
Rigsby, put out an APB on Lee Skelling.
He's armed and dangerous,
headed for the mountain regions.
Didn't do it.
Carnelian is a company
founded on good American values.
We will be a better company
because of this.
The sick individual behind this campaign
against us will not affect us in any way.
We will not be intimidated.
Fool.
Playing the hero. He'll get himself killed.
Carnelian needs to turn this
to their PR advantage...
- ...or their business will lose money.
- How's Carnelian's stock?
Down 15 percent
since Whittaker's death.
Wow, I wonder whether anyone
made money off the drop.
- Shorting the stock you mean?
- Yeah.
If you'd known Carnelian
was gonna be targeted by Joe Public...
...because you are Joe Public...
...betting against them on the market
is easy money.
Can't be SkelLing. He's got no money.
It's not Skelling. We know that already.
You know that.
We're keeping an open mind.
On it. I'll run the market trading logs.
See if anybody made a killing,
so to speak.
Any word on Skelling?
Couple potential sightings
in the Mount Whitney area.
Parks services are all over it.
We'll get him.
I doubt it.
Skelling's in his element up there.
His survivalist fantasy life come true.
He's gone aground like a grizzly bear.
Eureka. I found a trading account that
made a series of moves in the market...
...against Carnelian stock.
- The trades exactly mirror our time line.
- There a name attached to the account?
There's a subsidiary track
to a British bank.
A company account
in the name of NS Holdings.
NS? Nadia Sobell.
Aha.
We're looking for Nadia Sobell.
She's on the mountain with the others,
playing war.
- War?
- Yeah, you know, those paintball guns?
You divide into teams, get dressed up
and creep around trying to kill each other.
It's actually a lot of fun.
If only I hadn't twisted my ankle.
So, what do you guys want
to talk to Nadia for?
Nadia?
Hey.
Nadia.
Oh, my God.
Okay, thanks, guys.
- What do we have?
- Body went to the lab a couple hours ago.
Local PD's working a search
at the scene.
- Any word on Skelling?
- Nothing recent.
Last sighting of him was mid-morning
at a trailhead three and a half miles...
...from where Sobell was shot.
He could have made it, easy.
- Coincidence. He didn't do it.
- We don't... Never mind.
- Whoever did this thinks we're idiots.
- Yes. A mistake.
How so? We look like idiots when
our number one suspect gets shot...
- ...practically right in front of us.
- Not in front of us.
- Any messages from Joe Public?
- Not a word.
Won't hear from him.
That disguise has grown boring,
I suspect.
Joe Public's a ruse? What's the motive
for killing Whittaker and Sobell?
Yes, well, that's the question.
Whittaker's death was random.
Any of them could have taken
the dud chute.
But Sobell's wasn't.
What does that tell us?
- What? We give up.
- Well, I'm not entirely sure.
- Are Faulk and the others still inside?
- Yeah.
- What's in the bag?
- Oh. Picnic lunch.
- A bomb.
Ha, ha.
- What's in the bag, seriously?
- Seriously, a bomb.
What happened?
Sobell and I were competing
against De Shaun and Joyce.
I was tracking Joyce
when I heard the shot.
And then I heard De Shaun yelling
from over the ridge.
Mr. Faulk? Your cars are here
and the baggage is loaded.
- Thank you, Jake.
- You're leaving?
Yes. It was a mistake to stay.
I was tempting fate to prove a point,
and now poor Nadia has paid for it.
- It's too much.
- You can't blame yourself.
Why not?
- Excuse me?
- No, it's all right.
The barb is well placed. I've been wrong.
The company's been wrong.
I need to issue a statement.
Make an apology.
No. No, you can't let this psycho win.
No, not to Joe Public,
to the general public. The people.
Carnelian is gonna change its ways
and become a better company.
Redeemed by its suffering.
Reborn, rebranded.
Ethical, honest, clean.
- That's brilliant.
- Yes, it is. It's brilliant.
No, it's just necessary.
I want a campaign on those themes
ready by next week.
I got a phone call from Van Pelt.
Forensics got a hit on the bullet
taken out of Sobell.
It's a boat-tail .264 caliber bullet
manufactured by Winchester in 1989.
Part of a custom batch
given to the top 10 finalists...
...in the Annual American Cowboy
Shootist competition in Reno, Nevada.
- You're kidding.
- Let me guess.
- Jake Cooby.
- Seventh place.
- Jake Cooby? The ranch manager?
- Of course. It all adds up.
- It's perfect.
- It is?
- Why would Cooby wanna kill somebody?
- Well, let's go ask him.
Mr. Faulk, where does Mr. Cooby
put his feet up?
- The staff kitchen.
- Thank you.
Wait.
Why is Jake involved?
The bullet that killed Nadia,
apparently very special.
Almost certainly belongs to Mr. Cooby.
Jake? Can't be.
- You know him well?
- I've been coming here for six years.
We're good friends. This is a good man.
Salt of the earth. This can't be.
Forensics doesn't lie.
He never expressed animosity
toward you?
No. Never.
Must be a secret grudge.
Staff kitchen, you said. This way?
- Maybe you can help us.
- Of course.
- Come with me when I talk to Mr. Cooby.
- All right.
Hold on. I don't think
that's such a good idea.
It's him that Cooby's angry with.
Let's use that. Vex him.
- Open him up a little.
- It's too risky.
You can wait outside with your gun drawn
in case Cooby gets a little haywire.
You saying it's me? I shot her?
Yes, and cut Whittaker's parachute,
and planted the bomb...
- ...that almost killed Mr. Faulk here.
- I surely did not.
- Jeez, why in heck would I do all that?
- That's what we'd like to know.
Are you guys for real? Come on.
How long have you known me, Mr. Faulk?
Why, Jake?
What did I ever do to you to justify this?
Help me understand.
Okay. Now, see here.
I don't know how,
but you got the wrong idea about me.
Is that right?
Then why was it that one of your
prize bullets killed Nadia Sobell?
- It was?
- And why did you build this clever thing?
What? is that a bomb?
- Yes, Jake, it's your bomb. You made it.
- No, I didn't.
- What have you been smoking, man?
- Really? No? It's not?
This is not your trigger?
- Oh, for God's sakes.
- Is that...?
It's okay. Everyone just stay calm.
It's no problem.
I'm pretty sure you disarm it by removing
this wire from the red terminal...
No. Idiot.
There. What the hell are you playing at?
Aha.
- As they say.
- What are you talking about?
You knew how to disarm the bomb.
Because you made it.
You planted it to divert suspicion
from yourself.
Ergo, it was you that killed Whittaker
and Sobell.
I hate to spoil your theory,
but it's obvious how to disarm the bomb.
No, it wasn't. I bet 90 percent of people
would think to remove this wire here...
No!
The bomb squad took out the explosive.
That's just Play-Doh.
And you are a wretched, scheming,
cold-hearted murderer.
- Where do you keep your tea?
- In the cabinet.
- You're mad.
- Thank you.
Oh, and could you please ask
Agent Lisbon to come in?
Thanks, Mr. Cooby.
- You have no legal proof whatsoever.
- Eh.
Legal proof will be found, no doubt.
But personally, I don't need it.
I just like to know that I'm right.
Sir, put your hands behind your back.
You're under arrest. Let's go.
I knew it was you as soon as the bomb
under your bed failed.
- It was too clever, Randy. Too clever.
- Don't call me Randy.
But why would you randomly
wanna kill one of your own executives?
Doesn't make sense.
Then Sobell was shot
and I saw your whole game, Randy.
That's very childish.
Whittaker's death was merely camouflage
to disguise Sobell's death.
She's who you needed dead.
I won't say anything
until my lawyer arrives.
Suffice to say, you have no proof.
The question is,
what did Sobell have on you?
- What was she going to do?
- Nothing.
That was a rhetorical question.
We know everything we need to now.
This is an affidavit
from Nadia Sobell's lawyer.
Nadia was secretly negotiating
to join KBT...
...your number one rival. She was also
drafting a sexual-harassment suit...
...against you to coincide
with her departure.
That's why she was shorting
Carnelian stock. You needed to kill her.
Because nobody gets on top
of Randall Faulk, do they?
Nobody.
Where's my lawyer?
But I gotta tell you,
the whole Joe Q Public ruse, genius.
I couldn't see how you could profit
from attacking your own company.
But you, you have vision.
Carnelian reborn and rebranded.
Everybody loves a comeback.
Everybody loves redemption.
- You have nothing.
- Enough to rip you to pieces.
And you know it.
So before your lawyer gets here...
...and ties everybody's hands,
let's make a deal.
- I'm listening.
- Good.
We'll call Whittaker manslaughter one.
We'll forget about the bomb...
...and we won't go after
the death penalty.
In exchange for what?
Bills.
What's this?